<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en">
	<Esri>
		<CreaDate>20220322</CreaDate>
		<CreaTime>17485000</CreaTime>
		<ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat>
		<ArcGISstyle>ISO 19139 Metadata Implementation Specification</ArcGISstyle>
		<SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce>
		<ModDate>20220322</ModDate>
		<ModTime>17590400</ModTime>
		<scaleRange>
			<minScale>150000000</minScale>
			<maxScale>5000</maxScale>
		</scaleRange>
		<ArcGISProfile>ISO19139</ArcGISProfile>
		<DataProperties>
			<itemProps>
				<imsContentType export="False">
				</imsContentType>
			</itemProps>
		</DataProperties>
	</Esri>
	<dataIdInfo>
		<resConst>
			<Consts>
				<useLimit>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This dataset is released under Creative Commons by Attribution 4.0 International (CC BY 4.0).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</useLimit>
			</Consts>
		</resConst>
		<idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Consistent with the Australian Government's commitment to develop a National Representative System of Marine Protected Areas, networks of marine parks have been proclaimed for Commonwealth waters across the North, North-west, South-west, Temperate East and Coral Sea Marine Regions and, most recently, in the Indian Ocean Territories. These networks build on previous marine protected area proclamations, including the South-east Marine Parks Network declared in 2007. This data contains spatial and contextual information about Australian Marine Parks proclaimed under the Commonwealth Government's Environment Protection and Biodiversity Conservation Act 1999, which are managed by Parks Australia, with the addition of Heard Island and McDonald Islands Marine Reserve, which is managed by the Australian Antarctic Division &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;http://www.heardisland.aq/protection-and-management/marine-reserve&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This dataset does not include data on marine protected areas in other Australian jurisdictions (e.g. the Great Barrier Reef Marine Park, State/Territory marine parks), or terrestrial protected areas with marine components (e.g. Pulu Keeling National Park). &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;More information can be found at http://parksaustralia.gov.au/marine&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Since the Australian Marine Parks dataset was originally published in 2018 there have been the following updates:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;1. A technical amendment was made on the basis of user feedback (April 30th 2019). Macquarie Island was the only marine park affected by this amendment. The area calculation for Macquarie Island Marine Park was previously under reported by 483km2. This will have affected statistical analyses that used the calculated area (KM2) as an input. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;2. A zoning boundary error identified at West Island in Ashmore Reef Marine Park was corrected (March 2022).&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;3. Two new Australian Marine Parks were added to this dataset in March 2022; Christmas Island Marine Park and Cocos (Keeling) Islands Marine Park.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs>
		<idCredit>Australian Marine Parks © Commonwealth of Australia, Australian Government Department of Agriculture, Water and the Environment, 2022</idCredit>
		<idCitation>
			<resTitle>Australian Marine Parks - North-west Network</resTitle>
			<date>
				<createDate>2018-01-25T00:00:00</createDate>
				<reviseDate>2022-03-22T00:00:00</reviseDate>
			</date>
		</idCitation>
		<dataLang>
			<languageCode value="eng">
			</languageCode>
		</dataLang>
		<dataChar>
			<CharSetCd value="004">
			</CharSetCd>
		</dataChar>
		<tpCat>
			<TopicCatCd value="003">
			</TopicCatCd>
		</tpCat>
		<tpCat>
			<TopicCatCd value="014">
			</TopicCatCd>
		</tpCat>
	</dataIdInfo>
	<mdHrLv>
		<ScopeCd value="005">
		</ScopeCd>
	</mdHrLv>
	<mdLang>
		<languageCode value="eng">
		</languageCode>
	</mdLang>
	<mdChar>
		<CharSetCd value="004">
		</CharSetCd>
	</mdChar>
	<mdDateSt>20220322</mdDateSt>
	<mdContact>
		<editorSource>external</editorSource>
		<editorDigest>6ffe2c1c71373cdf897d7b99208ecca</editorDigest>
		<rpOrgName>Australian Government Department of Agriculture, Water and the Environment</rpOrgName>
		<rpPosName>Marine Data Manager</rpPosName>
		<rpCntInfo>
			<cntPhone>
				<voiceNum tddtty="">02 6274 1111</voiceNum>
				<faxNum>02 6274 1666</faxNum>
			</cntPhone>
			<cntAddress addressType="postal">
				<delPoint>GPO Box 787</delPoint>
				<city>Canberra</city>
				<adminArea>ACT</adminArea>
				<postCode>2601</postCode>
				<country>AU</country>
				<eMailAdd>geospatial@awe.gov.au</eMailAdd>
			</cntAddress>
			<cntOnlineRes>
				<linkage>http://www.environment.gov.au/</linkage>
			</cntOnlineRes>
		</rpCntInfo>
		<editorSave>True</editorSave>
		<displayName>Australian Government Department of Agriculture, Water and the Environment</displayName>
		<role>
			<RoleCd value="002">
			</RoleCd>
		</role>
	</mdContact>
	<dqInfo>
		<dataLineage>
			<statement>Australian Marine Parks have been created in accordance with the Australian Government's 'Goals and Principles for the Establishment of the National Representative System of Marine Protected Areas in Commonwealth Waters'. Boundaries of the areas are based on analysis done by the Department of Agriculture, Water and the Environment of key environmental and socio-economic data.

The lines that make up the reserve boundaries were created/sourced as described below:

- parallels and meridians were generated in ArcGIS and then densified to 0.025 decimal degrees (approx. 2.5km) prior to incorporation with other linework. 
- intermediate points along geodesic lines (note that, geodesic lines are the shortest line between points, they are not lines of constant bearing) were generated. A maximum segment length of 5km was used, which for this data ensures geodesic lines are within 1 metre of their true position.
- maritime boundaries were sourced from AMB 2014a v3.0 (Geoscience Australia).
- for Cocos (Keeling) Islands marine park, 30k coastline data (Geoscience Australia, 2010) was used to approximate the high water mark that describes part of the park boundary within the lagoon at South Keeling Islands. Orthophotography (Geoscience Australia, 2011) and 2011 coastline data (Geoscience Australia) were also used to derive the park boundaries of the two National Park Zones at South Keeling Islands
- for the Christmas Island marine park, the inner boundary of the park was defined using three data sources; the Collaborative Australian Protected Areas database (DAWE, 2021), Normal Baselines Limit (AMB 2014a v3.0, Geoscience Australia) and the Port of Christmas Island boundary (created by DAWE as described in the Notice of Declaration of Security Regulated Port - Port of Christmas Island 2013).
 
For each Australian Marine Park, appropriate linework was generated and then used to construct polygons in ArcGIS.</statement>
		</dataLineage>
	</dqInfo>
</metadata>
